Subindex build by Linnet
http://linnet.126.com  http://blog.csdn.net/redbirdli
火鸟字幕合并器SubindexV0.5
Created time 13.12.07 23:19:51
你以为我在玩性虐待吗？
Do you find me sadistic?
知道吗，小妞儿…
You know, Kiddo...
我相信即使现在你还很清醒…
...I'd like to believe...
...you're aware enough, even now...
知道我不是在玩性虐待
...to know that there's nothing sadistic...
...in my actions.
此时此刻
At this moment...
是我…
...this is me...
最痛苦的时候
...at my most masochistic.
比尔
Bill.
这是你的骨肉
It's your ba...
你以为我死了？
Looked dead, didn't I?
我没死
Well, I wasn't.
但我是从鬼门关爬回来的
But it wasn't from lack of trying, I can tell you that.
事实上，比尔用最后一颗子弹让我昏迷
Actually, Bill's last bullet put me in a coma -
一场长达四年的昏迷
a coma I was to lie in for four years.
醒来以后
When I woke up, I went on what the movie advertisements refer to as
就开始了像电影广告词似的
“怒吼着疯狂的复仇”
"a roaring rampage of revenge. "
我怒吼了
I roared, and I rampaged,
也疯狂了
我从血腥中得到满足
and I got bloody satisfaction.
我杀了很多人才走到这个地步
I've killed a hell of a lot of people to get to this point,
只剩下一个人了
but I've only one more.
最后一个
The last one.
我正要开车去找他
The one I'm driving to right now.
唯一剩下的
The only one left.
等我到达了目的地
And when I arrive at my destination,
就要亲手杀死比尔
I am gonna kill Bill.
杀死比尔 第二卷
第六章 双松镇大屠杀
发生在双松镇的大屠杀
The incident that happened at the Two Pines Wedding Chapel
也就是这个血腥故事的导火线
that put this whole gory story into motion
如今已成追忆
has since become legend.
双松镇屠杀案
"Massacre at Two Pines. "
这是报纸的标题
That's what the newspapers called it.
当地电视新闻称之为
The local TV news called it,
德州埃尔帕索“结婚礼拜堂屠杀案”
"The El Paso, Texas Wedding Chapel Massacre. "
事发过程
How it happened, who was there,
谁在场
how many got killed and who killed them -
死了几个人、凶手是谁
各界的说词不一
changes depending on who's telling the story.
事实上
In actual fact, the massacre didn't happen during a wedding at all.
这根本不是婚礼大屠杀
那次是婚礼前的彩排
It was a wedding rehearsal.
等到我说“你可以亲吻新娘”时
Now, when we come to the part where I say,
"You may kiss the bride," you may kiss the bride.
你就可以亲吻新娘了
But don't stick your tongue in her mouth.
但别把舌头伸进她嘴里
你们的朋友或许觉得好笑
This might be funny to your friends,
但双方家长会面红耳赤
but it would be embarrassing to your parents.
牧师，我们会尽量克制自己
We'll try to restrain ourselves, Reverend.
要点歌吗？
Y'all got a song?
温柔地爱我如何？
How about "Love Me Tender"? I can play that.
那首我会弹
好啊
- Sure. - Yeah.
那首歌很好听
"Love Me Tender" would be great.
鲁弗斯很厉害
Rufus - he's the man.
鲁弗斯，你以前替谁演奏？
Rufus, who was that that you used to play for?
鲁弗斯・汤玛斯
Rufus Thomas.
Rufus Thomas. Rufus Thomas.
鲁弗斯・汤玛斯
I was a Drell. I was a Drifter. I was a Coaster.
还有德雷尔乐团
漂流者乐团
航海者乐团
库尔与伙伴乐团
I was part of the Gang. I was a Barkay.
Bar-Kay乐团
只要他们来德州
If they come through Texas, I done played with 'em.
我都会去伴奏
鲁弗斯
Rufus - he's the man.
他很厉害
我有没有漏了什么？
- Have I forgotten anything? - Um...
有，你漏了
Oh yes, you forgot, uh, the seating arrangements.
座位安排
母亲，谢谢你
- Thank you, Mother. - Yes.
通常在座位的安排上
Now, the way we normally do this -
分成新娘的家属
we have the bride's side, and then we have the groom's side.
以及新郎的家属两边
但这次新娘没有家属要来
But since the bride ain't got nobody comin',
而新郎
and the groom's got far too many people comin'...
却有太多家属要来
大老远从奥克拉荷马州赶来
Well, yeah, they're comin' all the way from Oklahoma.
没错
Right...
我倒不介意
Well, I don't see no problem with...
新郎的家属坐到新娘那边
...the groom's side sharing the bride's side.
母亲，你介意吗？
- Do you, Mother? - I don't have a problem with that.
我也无所谓
不过
But, uh...
若新娘能找家属来会更好
Honey, you know, it would be good if you had somebody come.
这是善意的表示嘛
You know, as a sign of good faith?
我没有家属
Well, I don't have anybody...
只有汤米
...except for Tommy and my friends.
和这几个朋友
你没有家人？
- You have no family? - Well, I'm workin' on changing that.
我正在努力啊
Mrs. Harmony, we're all the family this little angel's ever gonna need.
哈蒙尼太太
这个小天使有我们就够了
我不太舒服
I'm not feeling very well, and this bitch is starting to piss me off.
快被那个小姑娘烦死了
你们继续聊
So while y'all blather on, I'm gonna go outside and get some air.
我出去透透气
好的
OK. Um, uh, Reverend, sorry, uh...
牧师，不好意思
她要去透透气
- She's gonna go out and get some air. - Yeah. Given her delicate condition...
怀孕难免会不舒服
给她几分钟喘口气就没事了
She just needs a few minutes to get it together. She'll be OK.
好的
Right...
小妞儿
Hello, Kiddo.
你是怎么找到我的？
- How did you find me? - I'm the man.
我厉害啊
你来这里干嘛？
What are you doin' here?
我来干嘛？
What am I doin'?
我
Well...
刚才我在吹笛子
...moment ago I was playin' my flute.
此时此刻
At this moment...
我正在看着这双昏花的老眼
...I'm lookin' at the most beautiful bride these old eyes have ever seen.
这辈子看过最美的新娘
你为什么要来？
- Why are you here? - Last look.
见你最后一面
你不会惹事吧？
- Are you gonna be nice? - I've never been nice in my whole life.
我一辈子都在惹事
但这次会尽力
But I'll do my best to be sweet.
安分一点
Hmm.
我早就说过了
I always told you...
你安分起来最讨人喜欢
...your sweet side is you best side.
所以才会
I guess that's why you're the only one who's ever seen it.
只有你看过我安分的一面
你身怀六甲了
- So you got a bun in the oven. - Hmm.
我怀孕了
- I'm knocked up. - Jeez, Louise.
我的老天啊
那个小伙子的动作还真快
That young man of yours sure doesn't believe in wasting time, does he?
你见过汤米了吗？
Have you seen Tommy?
穿燕尾服那个？
- Big guy in the tux? - Yes.
对
Then I saw him.
见过了
我喜欢他的发型
I like his hair.
保证要安分喔
You promised you'd be nice.
我只说会尽力，这不算保证
No, I said I'd do my best. That's hardly a promise.
但你言之有理
But you're right.
那个小伙子是做什么的？
What does your young man do for a living?
他在埃尔帕索经营二手唱片行
He owns a used record store here in El Paso.
原来是音乐迷啊
- Ah. Music lover, eh? - He's fond of music.
他喜欢音乐
我们不都是吗？
Aren't we all?
你这些日子是在哪一行高就？
And what are you doing for a J-O-B these days?
我在唱片行工作
I work in the record store.
原来如此
Aso.
来龙去脉我忽然都豁然开朗了
It all suddenly seems so clear.
你喜欢吗？
- Do you like it? - Yeah. I like it a lot, smartass.
超喜欢的，自命不凡的家伙
可以整天听音乐
I get to listen to music all day...
整天聊音乐，酷得很
...talk about music all day. It's really cool.
很适合我女儿成长的一个环境
It's gonna be a great environment for my little girl to grow up in.
不像某些人只会周游列国
As opposed to jetting around the world, killing human beings,
四处杀人
只为了赚进大把钞票
and being paid vast sums of money?
没错
Precisely.
老友啊
Well, my old friend...
人各有志
...to each his own.
不过
However, all cockblockery aside...
废话就不多说了
我倒是想认识那个小伙子
I am looking forward to meeting your young man.
我很想看清楚一点
I happen to be, more or less, particular whom my gal marries.
我的女人要嫁给怎样的人
你想参加婚礼吗？
- You want to come to the wedding? - Only if I can sit on the bride's side.
条件是要让我坐在新娘这边
坐我这边会很寂寞
You'll find it a bit lonely on my side.
在你身边向来都很寂寞
Your side always was a bit lonely.
但我还是甘之如饴
But I wouldn't sit anywhere else.
你知道吗？
You know...
我梦见你了
...I had the loveliest dream about you...
汤米来了，叫我艾琳
Oh, here's Tommy! Call me Arlene.
你就是汤米吧
- You must be Tommy! - Uh-huh.
艾琳经常提到你
Arlene's told me so much about you.
你还好吧？
- Honey, you OK? - Oh, I'm fine.
我很好
Tommy, I'd like you to meet my father.
汤米，他是我爸
天哪
Oh, my God!
天哪，太好了
Oh, my God, this is great!
很高兴能见到你
I'm so glad to meet you, sir... uh, Dad.
爸爸
The name's Bill.
我叫比尔
很荣幸能见到你比尔
Well, it's great to meet you... Bill.
艾琳说你不能来
- Arlene told me you couldn't make it. - Surprise.
惊喜
That's my pop for ya. Always full of surprises.
我爸就是这样
爱制造惊喜
说到惊喜
Well, in the surprise department...
真是有其父必有其女
...the apple doesn't fall far from the tree.
你几时来的？
- When did you get in? - Just now.
刚到而已
- Did you come straight from Australia? - Of course.
直接从澳洲过来吗？
对啊
Daddy, I told Tommy that you were in Perth mining for silver, and...
爸，我跟汤米说你去珀斯挖银矿
谁也联络不到你
...no one could reach you.
幸好我还是赶来了
Lucky for us all, that's not the case.
告诉我
So...
这是怎么回事？
What's this all about? I've heard of wedding rehearsals,
我听说过婚礼彩排
倒没听过穿着结婚礼服彩排
but I don't believe I've ever heard of a wedding dress rehearsal before.
我们觉得
We thought,
花大钱租礼服，只穿一次太可惜了
"Why pay so much money for a dress you're only going to wear once?"
尤其艾琳穿起来美若天仙
Especially when Arlene looks so goddamn beautiful in it.
我们想多穿几次，捞个够本
So, I think we're going to try to get all the mileage we can out of it.
新郎在婚礼之前
Isn't it supposed to be bad luck forthe groom to see the bride
看到新娘穿着结婚礼服
in her wedding dress before the ceremony?
不是很不吉利吗？
我比较铁齿啦
Well, I guess I just believe in living dangerously.
我懂你的意思
I know just what you mean.
小伙子
Son. Some of us have places to be.
我们还有事忙耶
Sure do.
我们要再彩排一次
Look, we got to go through this one more time. So, why don't you have a s...
你先去
天哪
Oh, my God. What am I thinking? You should give her away!
我在想什么？你要陪新娘走红毯
汤米，我爸不喜欢来这一套
Tommy, that's not exactly Daddy's cup oftea.
让他和其他宾客坐在一起
I think Father would be much more comfortable
他会比较自在一点
- sitting with the rest of the guests. - Hmm. Really?
真的吗？
That's asking a lot.
我是能免则免啦
那就算了
Oh. OK. Well, forget it.
今晚一起吃饭庆祝一下呢？
But how about we go out to dinner tonight to celebrate?
条件是要由我请客
Only on the condition that I pay for everything.
没问题，我们先去彩排了
Deal. We got to do this now.
我可以旁观吗？
- Can I watch? - Absolutely. Have a seat.
当然可以，请坐
哪一边是新娘的家属？
- Which is the bride's side? - Right over here.
这一边
母亲，开始吧
Mother, here we go!
关于誓约的部份
Now son, about them vows...
比尔
Bill...
我只是想
- I just want... - You don't owe me a damn thing.
你对我毫无亏欠
既然你决定嫁给他
If he's the man you want...
那就去站在他身旁吧
...then go stand by him.
我漂亮吗？
- Do I look pretty? - Oh, yes.
漂亮
谢谢你
Thank you.
搞什么？
What the hell?
不！比尔！
No! Bill!
你是说她前后杀了88个保镖
You tellin' me she cut her way through 88 bodyguards before she got to O-Ren?
才和御莲正面对决？
不是真的有88个人啦
Nah, there wasn't really 88 of'em.
他们只是自称“疯狂88人组”
They just call themselves "The Crazy 88"
为什么？
- How come? - I don't know.
不知道
I guess they thought it sounded cool.
大概是觉得这个名号很响亮吧
反正
Any how, they all fell under her Hanzo sword.
他们都成了服部半藏的刀下魂
她有服部半藏的刀？
- She got a Hanzo sword? - He made one for her.
他替她铸造的
他不是立下毒誓不再铸刀吗？
Didn't he swear a blood oath to never make another sword?
看来
It would appear he has broken it.
他违背誓言了
日本人还真会记恨
Them Japs sure know how to hold a grudge, don't they?
又或许
Or maybe...
你就是会让人恨得牙痒痒的
...you just tend to bring that out in people.
我知道这样问很奇怪
I know this is a ridiculous question before I ask it,
在我说出口之前
你最近还有没有继续
but you haven't, by any chance, kept up with your... swordplay?
我
I, um...
好几年前就典当了
I pawned that years ago.
你把服部半藏的刀典当了？
You hocked a Hattori Hanzo sword?
对
Yep.
那是无价之宝耶
It was priceless.
可惜在埃尔帕索不是
Well, not in El Paso, it ain't.
在埃尔帕索只值250美元
In El Paso, I got me $250 for it.
我在脱衣舞酒吧里当保镖
I'm a bouncer in a titty bar, Bill.
若她想找我火拼
If she wants to fight with me, all she's got to do is come to the club
只要来酒吧里惹事就好了
and start some shit, and we'll be in a fight.
我知道我们很久没有
I know we haven't spoken in some time,
好好聊一下了
我们上次的对话也不太愉快
and the last time we spoke wasn't the most pleasant,
但你最好别再生我的气
but you've got to get over being mad at me,
你该害怕的是她
and start becoming afraid of,
因为她快来了
because she is coming, and she's coming to kill you.
她要来杀你
除非你让我帮忙
And unless you accept my assistance, I have no doubt she will succeed.
否则她一定会得逞
我不会推委塞责
I don't dodge guilt, and I don't Jew out of paying my comeuppance.
该承受的报应我都会面对
我们能不能
Can't we just... forget the past?
尽释前嫌？
那个女人
That woman...
要报仇的话顺理成章
...deserves her revenge.
而且
And...
我们也死得理所当然
...we deserve to die.
但话又说回来
But then again...
她也一样
...so does she.
所以
So I guess...
我们只能静观其变了
...we'll just see.
你说是吗？
Won't we?
第七章 宝拉・舒尔茨的孤坟
你又迟到了
Late again.
巴德，你看不懂时钟吗？
Budd, can't you tell time?
反正店里又没人
There ain't nobody in here, man.
是巴德吗？
- Is that Budd? - Yeah.
对
Tell him to get his fucking ass back here!
叫他给我滚进来
好的
OK.
巴德，拉里有话要跟你说
Budd, Larry'd like a word with ya.
吸一口，你就浑然忘我了，宝贝
Take a hit. Be somebody, baby.
你找我？
You looking for me?
我不知道你之前是在哪家洗车厂打工
I don't know what carwash you worked before you came here
可以让你迟到二十分钟
that let you stroll in 20 minutes late, but it wasn't owned by me
但那家店的老板反正不是我
- and I own a fuckin' carwash. - Do you want me to leave?
要我回避吗？
No, I don't want you to leave. I want you to sit and wait.
不必，坐着等我
拉里
Larry...
店里又没人
...there ain't nobody out there, so...
"There's nobody out there, Larry. "
拉里，店里又没人
你想说什么？
What's your point?
这里没你的事吗？
- That you're not needed here? - My point is...
我的重点是…
我是保镖
...I'm the bouncer, and there ain't nobody out there to bounce.
这里没人需要我保护啊
你的意思是？
You're saying that the reason...
你之所以没有做好…
...that you're not doing the job that I'm...
我花钱请你来做的事
...paying you to do is that you don't have a job to do?
是因为你没事可做？
不是啦
- No... - Is that what you're saying?
是这个意思吗？
你想说服我什么？
What are you trying to convince me of, exactly?
你在我这里只是装饰用的？
That you're as useless as an asshole right here?
巴德，这样吧
Well, guess what, buddy.
我觉得
I think... you just fucking convinced me.
你刚才说服了我
我们看看日历
Let's go to the calendar.
看看日历吧
It's calendartime.
巴德该看看日历了
Calendartime for Buddy.
好，你明天要上班吗？
- OK. You working tomorrow? - Yeah.
要
Mm. No, you're n... You don't even know whatfucking day you work.
不对
你连哪天要上班都不知道
好，你明天没班，星期三才要来
Here. You're notworking tomorrow.
好了
You're working Wednesday. Here you are. There you go.
星期四要上班吗？
- Workin' Thursday? - Yeah.
要
I don't think so. Friday.
不必吧
星期五呢？
上面有你的名字
I d... There's your name.
你说了就算
- If you say so. - There used to be your name. OK?
本来有你的名字
星期六本来有你的名字
- Saturday. There used to be your name. - Oh.
你星期一要
Uh, Monday...
就这样，如何？
Here. How about that?
非得让你赚不到钱，才算给你教训
Fuckin' with your cash is the only thing you kids seem to understand. OK?
是吗？
你回家去等我的电话
Now, I want you to go home till I call you.
没等到就不必来了
Till I call you.
走之前去找火箭，她有事要你做
Before you leave, talk to Rocket. She's got a job for you to do.
还有
And...
那顶帽子
...the hat.
他妈的烂帽子
That fuckin' hat.
That fucking...
要我讲几次？
How many times have I told you,
不准戴那顶帽子来上班
don't wear that fucking hat here? How many?
要讲几次？
客人都戴帽子啊
Customers wear hats.
我不是客人的老板
Well, I'm not the boss of the customers.
我是你的老板
I'm the boss of you. And I'm telling you...
告诉你
那顶烂帽子你只准在家里戴
...that I want you to keep that shit-kicker hat at home.
巴德，马桶又塞住了
Yeah. Budd, honey, uh, the toilet is at it again.
粪水流得满地都是
There's shitty water all over the floor.
好的
OK... Rocket.
火箭
我去通马桶
- I'll clean it up. - Mm-hmm.
好了
Now...
你总算冷静下来了吧
...that gentled you down some, didn't it?
很好
Yep.
没人会坏到这种程度
Ain't nobody a badass with a double dose of rock salt dug deep in their tits.
发射了两枪岩盐
正中你的胸部
反正我
Not havin'... tits...
没有
像你这么漂亮
...as fine...
又这么丰满的胸部
...or as big as yours,
很难想像你会有多痛
I can't even imagine how bad that shit must sting.
不过
Yet...
我可不想亲身体验
...I don't want to, neither.
我赢了
I win.
Ugh! Ugh.
比尔？
Bill.
我是他老弟，死贱人
Wrong brother, ya hateful bitch.
巴德
- Budd. - Bingo.
答对了
请问你有何贵干？
And to what do I owe this dubious pleasure?
我刚才逮到了
I just caught me the cowgirl ain't never been caught.
你们一直抓不到的小妞儿
你杀了她吗？
- Did you kill her? - Well, not yet, I ain't.
还没有
只用岩盐射中她而已
I shot her full of rock salt.
她现在温驯得很
She's so gentle right now, I could perform her coup de grace with a rock.
随手拿块石头就能让她安乐死
不废话了
Anywho...
猜猜我手里拿着什么
Guess what I'm holdin' in my hand right now?
什么？
What?
服部半藏全新铸造的武士刀
A brand spankin' new Hattori Hanzo sword.
艾尔，我可以告诉你
And I'm here to tell ya, Elle,
什么才叫作锋利
- ... that's what I call sharp. - How much?
多少钱？
Oh, that's hard to say, bein' that it's... priceless and all.
很难说耶
因为这是无价之宝
有什么条件？
What's the terms?
你明天一大早就给我滚过来
You get your bony ass down here first thing in the morning...
带着一百万美元的纸钞
...with a million dollars in folding cash...
我就给你
...and I'll give you the greatest sword ever made by a man.
服部半藏亲手铸造的一等名刀
你意下如何？
Now, how do you like the sound of that?
成交了
Sounds like we got a deal.
不过有一个条件
- One condition. - What?
什么条件？
She must suffer to her last breath.
要让她受苦受难
直到咽下最后一口气为止
这个嘛
Well...
亲爱的艾尔
That, Elle darlin'...
我能保证让你如愿以偿
...I can pretty much damn well guarantee.
那我们就明天见了
Then I'll see you in the mornin', millionaire.
百万富翁
没问题
All right.
起床
Wakey, wakey.
吃早餐了
Eggs and bakey.
挖好了
I'm done!
拉我一把
Get me outta this hole!
Good.
Whew.
你看看她的眼神
Whoa, look at those eyes.
可凶猛了
This bitch is furious.
我不是说过了吗？
What did I tell ya?
你很难找到这么漂亮的金发小妞儿
Is she the cutest little blond pussy you ever saw?
对吧？
Or... is she the cutest little blond pussy you ever saw?
很难找到这么漂亮的金发小妞儿
我看过更漂亮的
I seen better.
你有什么话要说吗？
You got anything to say?
白种女人就是喜欢怒而不言
White women call this "the silent treatment. "
其实这样更合我们的意
And we let 'em think we don't like it.
你抓脚，我抓头
You grab the feet, I'll get the head.
Hey. Hey. Hey!
真会扭啊
Wiggle worm, you see this?
看见没？
看见了吧？
You see it, don't ya?
这是防身喷雾
That's a can of Mace.
Mm-hmm. No.
不，今晚要活埋你
You're goin' underneath the ground tonight.
就这么决定了
And... that's all there is to it.
我要活埋你
I wanna bury ya.
本来想给你
I was gonna bury ya...
这个当陪葬品
...with this.
但你再这样不好好合作
But if you're gonna act like a horse's ass...
我就要拿这整罐防身喷雾
...I'm gonna spray this whole goddamn can right in your eyeballs!
喷进你的眼睛里
让你两眼灼烧疼痛
I'll burn 'em right outta your fuckin' head.
然后两眼全盲
Then you're gonna be blind...
灼烧疼痛
...and burnin'...
被活埋
...and buried alive.
你打算怎样？
Now, what's it gonna be, sister?
算你识相
That's a wise decision.
你伤了我哥的心，我替他报仇
This is for breakin' my brother's heart.
第八章 白眉的磨难试炼
很久以前
Once upon a time...
在中国大陆
...in China...
据说
...some believe around the year...
在公元1003年左右
...one double aught-three,
白莲教的掌门人白眉道长
head priest of the White Lotus Clan, Pai Mei, was walking down a road...
走在路上的时候
不知道在沉思什么
...contemplating whatever it is
就是功力高强如白眉的人
that a man of Pai Mei's infinite powers would contemplate -
会沉思的事
换言之，就是天晓得他在想什么
which is another way of saying, "Who knows?" -
此时有个少林武僧走过来
when a Shaolin monk appeared on the road,
正好和他背道而行
traveling in the opposite direction.
少林武僧和白眉擦肩而过时
As the monk and the priest crossed paths...
白眉
...Pai Mei...
怀着高深莫测的宽宏大量
...in a practically unfathomable display of generosity,
向少林武僧微微颔首
gave the monk the slightest of nods.
结果对方没回礼
The nod...
...was not returned.
那位少林武僧
Now, was it the intention of the Shaolin monk to insult Pai Mei?
是故意轻蔑白眉？
或者只是没看到他点头示意？
Or did he just fail to see the generous social gesture?
那位少林武僧的动机
The motives of the monk remain unknown.
我们不得而知
只知道
What is known...
后果是怎样
...were the consequences.
隔天早上
The next morning, Pai Mei appeared at the Shaolin temple...
白眉来到了少林寺
命令少林寺住持
...and demanded of the temple's head abbot
在他面前自刎谢罪
that he offer Pai Mei his neck to repay the insult.
弥偿他所受的羞辱
起先少林寺住持想安抚白眉
The abbot, at first, tried to console Pai Mei.
结果发现白眉
Only to find Pai Mei was...
根本安抚不了
...inconsolable.
于是展开了
So began...
少林寺大屠杀
...the Massacre of the Shaolin Temple, and all sixty of the monks inside,
寺里的六十名僧侣全数遇害
死在白莲教掌门人的手下
at the fists of the White Lotus.
于是开始谣传起
And... so began the legend...
白眉的五步穿心指
...of Pai Mei's Five-Point-Palm Exploding-Heart Technique.
请问何谓“五步穿心指”？
And what, pray tell, is the Five-Point-Palm
很简单
- Exploding-Heart Technique? - Quite simply,
就是武术界最致命的绝招
the deadliest blow in all of martial arts.
用指尖点你的穴道
He hits you with his fingertips...
点身上的五个不同的穴位
...at five different pressure points on your body...
然后放你走
...and then lets you walk away.
但等你走了五步
But once you've taken five steps...
心脏就会在体内爆开
...your heart explodes inside your body...
瞬间倒地而死
...and you fall to the floor, dead.
他有教你吗？
- Did he teach you that? - No.
没有
他的五步穿心指从不外传
He teaches no one the Five-Point-Palm Exploding-Heart Technique.
说真的
Now...
我一直很欣赏你
...one of the things I've always liked about you...
小妞儿
...Kiddo...
你年纪轻轻就聪明过人
...is you appear wise beyond your years.
请容我给你几句忠告
So, allow me to impart a word to the wise:
无论如何
Whatever...
不管白眉说什么
...whatever Pai Mei says, obey.
你都要唯命是从
只要你眼神中略有叛意
If you flash him, even for an instant, a defiant eye, he'll pluck it out.
眼睛就会被他挖出来
若你用美国人的高傲姿态对他
And if you throw any American sass his way...
他会把你的颈背当树枝一样扭断
...he'll snap your back and your neck like they were twigs.
到时候你就呜呼哀哉了
And that will be the story of you.
他愿意收你为徒
He'll accept you as his student.
那你呢？
- What happened to you? - Nothin'.
没事
- Get in a fight? - Friendly contest.
打架了吗？
友谊赛
他为何收我为徒？
Why did he accept me?
因为他一只脚踏进棺材里
Because he's a very, very, very old man.
所有老不死的都一样
And like all rotten bastards...
等到死了
...when they become old, they get lonely.
就会很寂寞
不会影响他的脾气
Which has no effect on their dispositions,
只是这才发现有人作伴的重要
but it does teach them the value of company.
Whew. Oh.
光是再看到这段阶梯
Just seein' those steps again makes me ache.
我身体就凉了半截
你等着享受挑水
You're gonna have a lot of fun
上下这段阶梯的乐趣吧
carrying buckets of water up and down that fucker.
我们何时再相见？
When will I see you again?
那是我最爱的70年代灵魂歌曲
That's the title of my favorite soul song of the seventies.
什么？
- What? - Nothin'.
没事
等他说你学成了为止
When he tells me you're done.
你觉得要多久？
When do you think that might be?
这就要看你的造化了
That, my dearest, depends entirely on you.
记住
Now remember, no sarcasm, no backtalk.
不准嘲讽，不准回嘴
至少第一年要绝对服从
At least not for the first year or so.
先和他熟悉了再说
You're gonna have to let him warm up to you.
他讨厌白人
He hates Caucasians, despises Americans,
鄙视美国人
对女人更是轻蔑不屑
and has nothing but contempt for women.
所以你在这里
So, in your case... it might take a little while.
可能要待上好一阵子
再见
Adiós.
师父
Master...
你的汉语好差
Your Mandarin is lousy.
我一个字也听不懂，而且好刺耳
It causes my ears discomfort.
You bray like an ass!
我没要你说话，你就别说
You are not to speak unless spoken to.
你的汉语好呢，还是你的广东话好？
Is it too much to hope - you understand Cantonese?
我的日语很好
I speak Japanese very well-
我没问你日本话，也没问你蒙古话
I didn't ask if you speak Japanese -
我问你会不会说广东话？
I asked if you understand Cantonese?
一点点
A little.
你是来学武的，不是学讲话
You are here to learn the mysteries of Kung Fu, not linguistics.
如果你不懂汉语
If you can't understand me -
就像狗一样
I will communicate with you like I would a dog.
我会斥喝你，命令你，用棍打你
When I yell, when I point, when I beat you with my stick!
你的师父是不是比尔？
Bill is your master, is he not?
是的，是的
Yes, he is.
你师父说过你曾经学过武术
Your master tells me - you're not entirely unschooled.
你学过些什么？
What training do you possess?
我精通虎鹤拳
I am proficient in Tiger-Crane Style,
更精通日本武士道剑术
and I am more than proficient in the exquisite art of the Samurai sword.
哼，日本剑道，开什么玩笑
The exquisite art of the Samurai sword. Don't make me laugh!
你所谓的剑道不值个屁，你就更加笨
Your so-called exquisite art, is only fit for -
你居然敢正视我
Japanese fat heads!
看你的脾气都可以学武
Your anger amuses me. Do you believe you are my match?
你觉得本道的功夫跟你比如何？
不知
No.
你知道本道会杀人吗？
Are you aware I kill at will?
知道
Yes.
那么你是想死咯？
Is it your wish to die?
不
No.
傻瓜
Then you must be stupid...
真是傻瓜
Then you must be stupid... so stupid.
本道好想看看你有多傻
Rise, and let me look at your ridiculous face.
起身
Rise.
亏你还学过虎鹤拳
So my pathetic friend... Is there anything that you can do well?
刚才走了一百来台阶就在喘了
我看你不单是傻，身体也很虚啊
What's the matter?
Cat got yourtongue?
喔，对了，你会说日本话
- Oh yes, you speak Japanese.
我最恨日本人
I despise the Goddamn Japs!
去兵器架那边
Go to that rack.
拔那把剑
Remove the sword.
我要看下你的武功有多深
Let's see how good you really are.
出招
If...
如果我输给你的话
...you land a single blow,
我干脆拜你为师
I'll bow down and call you master.
你看到我的功夫了吧，试我的脚法
From here you can get an excellent view of my foot.
你的剑术只是一般入门的水平
Your swordsmanship - is amateur at best.
残废也比你强
Your so-called kung-fu - is really - quite pathetic.
我已经给你机会显示一下你的武功
I asked you to demonstrate - what you know - and you did...
我看到了
你一点都不会
Not a goddamn thing!
现在我要你以虎鹤拳
Let's see yourTiger Crane - match my Eagle's Claw.
和我的鹰爪拳比试一下
你和其他美国女人一样
Like all Yankee women...
只知道在餐馆点菜
...all you can do is order in restaurants and spend a man's money.
花男人的钱
痛吗？我问你呢？
Excruciating - isn't it?
痛
Yes!
你相不相信我
If it was my wish...
随时能砍下你的手臂
...I could chop your arm off.
不，求求你不要！
No, please don't!
你相不相信我想怎样就怎样
It's my arm now. I can do what I please.
如果你不想我砍你的手，动手
If you can stop me - I suggest you try.
我不行
I can't.
打不过吧？
Because you're helpless?
对
Yes.
你以前试过这种滋味吗？
Have you ever felt this before?
没有
No.
你的功夫和我比，简直是班门弄斧
Compared to me - you're as helpless as a worm fighting an eagle?
对
YES!
现在开始
THAT'S THE BEGINNING!
你想不想学，我刚才和你打的这套拳？
Is it your wish to possess this kind of power?
想
Yes!
从明天开始你要练武
Your training will begin - tomorrow.
记住
你的手臂属于我
Since your arm now belongs to me...
我会将它练得结实
...I want it strong.
你能不能做到像我这样？
Can you do that?
可以，但那么近没办法
I can, but not that close.
那就是不行了
Then you can't do it.
如果敌人离你的身体只有三寸
What if your enemy - is three inches in front of you...
你怎么对付他？
...What do you do then...
抱头鼠窜
...Curl into a ball...
还是用拳打穿他？
...or do you put your FIST through him?
现在开始
Now begin.
练拳头不应该是你怕木头
It's the wood that should fear your hand -
应该是木头怕你
- not the otherway around.
你之所以打不穿木头
No wonder you can't do it - you acquiesce to defeat -
是因为你用手之前已经认输了
- before you even begin.
如果你像狗一样吃东西
If you want to eat like a dog...
我就让你像狗一样住外面
You can live and sleep outside like a dog.
如果你想像人一样的话
If you want to live and sleep like a human...
把筷子拿起来
...pick up those sticks.
快，你这混蛋
Come on, you bitch.
好了，白眉
OK, Pai Mei.
看我的吧
Here I come.
请给我一杯水
May I have a glass of water, please?
第九章 艾尔与我
那是德州式的葬礼？
- So that's a Texas funeral? - Yep.
对
巴德，我真服了你
I have to give it to ya, Budd.
那种死法真要命
That's a pretty fucked up way to die.
墓碑上写的是什么名字？
What's the name on the grave she's buried under?
宝拉
Paula...
舒尔茨
...Schultz.
可以看看武士刀吗？
Can I look at the sword?
红色行李箱装的是我的钱吗？
That's my money right there in that red bag, isn't it?
没错
It sure is.
那武士刀就是你的了
Well then, it's your sword now.
这就是服部半藏铸的刀啊
你说什么？
What's that you said?
这就是服部半藏铸的刀啊
So this is a Hattori Hanzo sword.
那是服部半藏铸的没错
That's a Hanzo sword, all right.
比尔说你以前也有他铸的刀
Bill tells me you once had one of these of your own.
对，曾经有过
Yeah, once.
和这把刀比起来呢？
Yeah? How does this one compare to that?
若想比较服部半藏铸的刀
If you're gonna compare a Hanzo sword...
就要和其他那些
...you compare it to every other sword ever made -
不是服部半藏
wasn't made - by Hattori Hanzo.
铸造的武士刀比较
拿去，喝喝看
Here you go. Wrap your lips around that.
你
So...
现在的心情如何？
...which "R" are you filled with?
什么？
What?
有人说
They say...
人老了以后的头号敌人
...the number one killer...
...of old people...
就是退休
...is retirement.
每个人都要工作
People got a job to do, they tend to live a little bit longer so they can do it.
为了工作
才会活得更久一点
我一直觉得
I've always figured that...
战士和他们的敌人
...warriors and their enemies...
也是这样的关系
...share the same relationship.
既然你不必再和敌人短兵相接了
So now that you're not gonna have to face your enemy no more
on the battlefield...
现在的心情如何？
...which "R" ya filled with?
松了一口气？
Relief...
还是遗憾？
...or regret?
两种都有吧
- A little bit of both. - Horseshit.
胡扯
我当然知道两种都有
I'm sure you do feel a little bit of both.
但我相信其中一种感觉
But I know damn well that you feel one...
一定比另一种感觉更强烈
...more than you feel the other.
我要问的是
And the question was: Which one is it?
哪一种？
遗憾
Regret.
那个小妞儿真有一套
You know, you gotta hand it to the ol' girl.
没看过有人比她更让比尔着迷
I never saw anybody buffalo Bill the way she buffaloed Bill.
比尔觉得她聪明绝顶
Bill thought she was so damn smart.
我早就想告诉他了
And I tried to tell him...
她只是在金发小妞儿里算聪明的
...she was just smart for a blond.
谢了
Thanks a bunch.
All right.
Mmm.
抱歉
I'm sorry, Budd.
我太失礼了
That was rude of me, wasn't it?
巴德，这位是我的朋友
Budd, I'd like to introduce my friend, the black mamba.
黑曼巴
黑曼巴，这位是巴德
Black mamba, this is Budd.
我在买下这条蛇之前
You know, before I picked that little fella up,
还上网查过资料
I looked him up on the Internet.
黑曼巴非常特别
Fascinating creature, the black mamba.
你听听看
Listen to this:
非洲有句俗话说
"In Africa, the saying goes,
在丛林里会被大象踩死
"'In the bush, an elephant can kill you, a leopard can kill you,
会被豹咬死
也会被黑曼巴毒死
"'and a black mamba can kill you. But only with the mamba,
但只有黑曼巴
在非洲从互古至今始终不变
"and this has been true in Africa since the dawn of time, is death sure. '
保证致命
所以又名为…
Hence its handle, 'Death Incarnate. "' Pretty cool, huh?
死神的化身
很酷吧？
其神经毒素是自然界的剧毒之一
"Its neurotoxic venom is one of nature's most effective poisons,
作用于神经系统可能导致瘫痪
"acting on the nervous system, causing paralysis.
黑曼巴的毒液
"The venom of a black mamba can kill a human being in four hours
能在四小时内致人于死
这是在脚踝或拇指被咬的情况下
"if, say, bitten on the ankle or the thumb.
不过
"However, a bite to the face or torso
被咬到脸部或躯干
can bring death from paralysis within 20 minutes. "
二十分钟内就会瘫痪至死
这段你要仔细听因为和你有关
Now, you should listen to this, 'cause this concerns you.
咬一口注入的毒液量
"The amount of venom that can be delivered from a single bite
就能让人回天乏术了
can be gargantuan."
我很喜欢“回天乏术”这个成语
You know, I've always liked that word, "gargantuan."
只是苦无机会可以使用
I so rarely have an opportunity to use it in a sentence.
如不即刻施打抗毒血清
"If not treated quickly with antivenom,
十至十五毫克即可致人于死
"ten to 15 milligrams can be fatal to human beings.
但黑曼巴咬一口
"However, the black mamba can deliver
能注入一百至四百毫克的毒液
as much as 100 to 400 milligrams of venom from a single bite. "
现在
Now...
在你垂死痛苦挣扎的最后几分钟
...in these last agonizing minutes of life you have left,
我要仔细回答你刚才的问题
let me answer that question you asked earlier more thoroughly.
此时此刻
Right at this moment...
我最强烈的感觉是遗憾
...the biggest "R" I feel is regret.
遗憾
Regret that maybe the greatest warrior I have ever met
可能是我毕生最强悍的劲敌
居然会死在
met her end at the hands of a bushwhackin', scrub,
像你这种下三滥
卑鄙无耻小人的手上
alkie, piece of shit like you.
假你之手太侮辱她了
That woman deserved better.
比尔
Bill...
我有坏消息
...I have some tragic news.
你弟弟死了
Your brother's dead.
我很遗憾，宝贝
I am so sorry, baby.
她在屋里放了黑曼巴
She put a black mamba in his camper.
我替你报了仇，她也死了
I got her, sweetie. She's dead.
这么说吧
Let me put it this way:
每当你想念她时
You ever start feeling sentimental, go to Barstow, California.
就去加州的巴尔斯托
到那里先去当地的花店买一束花
When you get here, walk into a florist and buy a bunch of flowers.
带着那束花
Take those flowers to Huntington Cemetery
去富勒与瓜达卢普的亨廷顿墓园
on Fuller and Guadalupe, look for the headstone marked "Paula Schultz,"
找到宝拉・舒尔茨的墓碑
把花放在坟墓上
and lay them on the grave.
因为在坟墓里长眠的人
'Cause you will be standing at the final resting place of Beatrix Kiddo.
正是比阿特丽克斯小妞儿
马蒂・奇斯卓斯尔？
- Marty Kitrosser? - Here.
到
- Melanie Harrhouse? - Here.
梅兰妮・哈尔豪斯？
到
- Beatrix Kiddo? - Here.
比阿特丽克斯小妞儿？
到
我四个小时就到了
Look... I can be there in about four hours.
你要我过去吗？
Do you want me to come over?
不，如果你要，宝贝，我过去陪你
No, no, no. You need me, baby, I'm there.
好，我现在就出发
OK. I'm leaving now.
你去抽根大麻，我马上到
You go smoke some pot or somethin'. I'll be there soon.
Ugh.
恶心
Gross.
Hi-ya!
献给我的弟弟，巴德 我唯一爱的人
"To my brother, Budd. The only man I ever loved. Bill. "
比尔赠
那是什么？
What's that?
巴德的服部半藏武士刀
Budd's Hanzo sword.
他说拿去典当了
He said he pawned it.
想必他是骗你的了
Guess that makes him a liar now, don't it?
艾尔
- Elle? - Bea.
比阿特丽克斯
有件事我一直很好奇
Somethin' I've always been curious about.
算是咱们女孩间的秘密吧
Just between us girls...
你对白眉说了什么
...what did you say to Pai Mei to make him snatch out your eye?
他居然戳瞎了你一只眼睛？
Ow!
我骂他可怜的老不死
I called him a miserable old fool.
Ooh. Bad idea.
噢，馊主意
你知道我做了什么吗？
Know what I did?
我杀了那可怜的老不死
I killed that miserable old fool.
鱼头好不好吃啊
How do you like the fish head, you miserable old fool?
可怜的老不死？
I poisoned his fish heads.
我在他的鱼头里下毒
艾尔，你这条没人性的狗
Elle, you treacherous dog.
我一定会
I - give - you - my -word -
我告诉他
And I told him,
“对我来说，你这老不死的话
"To me, the word of an old fool like you
一文不值”
is worth less than nothing. "
没错
That's right.
我杀了你师父
I killed your master.
现在我要杀了你
And now I'm gonna kill you, too.
用你随身的武士刀
With your own sword, no less.
再过不了多久
Which, in the very immediate future, will become my sword.
这把刀就是我的了
婊子
Bitch...
你马上就玩完了
...you don't have a future.
Fucking bitch!
我看不见！
臭婊子！
我要杀了你！
I'll kill you! You're fuckin' dead!
婊子！
You bitch! You bitch!
我要杀了你！你他妈的死定了！
走着瞧！
I'll fucking kill you, you bitch!
我要杀了你！
你在哪里？
Oh, I'll get you!
我们走着瞧！
你在哪里？等着接招吧！
I'm gonna...
你死定了！
Where are you? Lemme fuckin' at you!
我要杀了你这个…你在哪
Where are you? I'm coming, you fucking bitch!
可恶！该死的婊子
该死的…
You're fucking dead! You're dead!
Oh... shit!
最终章 面对面
和大多数从小不知道他们父亲的人一样
Like most men who never knew their father,
比尔喜欢有长者风范的人
Bill collected father figures.
第一个就是埃斯特班・维埃欧
The first was Esteban Vihaio.
埃斯特班以前是皮条客
Esteban was a pimp and a friend of Bill's mother.
也是比尔母亲的朋友
He ran a brothel in Acuna, Mexico, for over 50 years.
他在墨西哥阿库纳
经营妓院五十几年
他的保镖团“阿库纳小子”
His army, the Acuna Boys,
清一色都是没爹的妓女后代
made up of the fatherless offspring of his whores, ran Acuna.
在阿库纳占地为王
阿库纳小子都归他管
He ran the Acuna Boys.
如今他高龄八十岁
Now, at the age of 80, it would be this retired gentleman of leisure
这位已经退休的老绅士
可以指引我找到比尔
who could point me in Bill's direction.
埃斯特班・维埃欧先生吗？
Se?or Esteban Vihaio?
是的
Yes.
我可以坐吗？
May I join you?
条件是你要叫我埃斯特班
Only on the condition that you call me Esteban.
我可以坐吗，埃斯特班？
- May I join you, Esteban? - Please.
请坐
美国人吗？
Americana?
对
Yes.
我懂一点点西班牙语
I speak a little Spanish, if you prefer.
不必了
No, no, no, no. I prefer English.
讲英文就好了
我很久没讲英文
I haven't spoken it in a while,
但我很珍惜能有这个机会
but I would relish the opportunity to converse
和此等的美女聊天
with such a pretty companion as yourself.
能和你这种绅士闲谈是我的荣幸
It's my pleasure to be in the company of such a fine gentleman as yourself.
小姐，我要警告你
I must warn you, young lady...
随便夸我几句我就会得寸进尺
...I am susceptible to flattery.
请问有何贵干？
How may I be of service to you?
比尔在哪儿？
Where's Bill?
Ahh.
你是比阿特丽克斯吧
You must be Beatrix.
看得出来比尔看上你哪一点
I can see the attraction.
还记得比尔才五岁时
I remember when Bill was only five years old, I took him to the movies.
我带他去看电影
那是一部拉娜・特纳主演的电影
It was a movie starring Lana Turner.
邮差总按两次铃
The Postman Always Ring Twice, with John Garfields.
男主角是约翰・加菲尔德
每次她出现在荧幕上时
And whenever she would appear on the screen,
比尔就会情不自禁地
Bill would begin compulsively to suck his thumb to an obscene amount.
猛吸他的大拇指
我从那时候就发现这个小子
And I knew from this very moment, this boy was a fool for blonds.
超级迷恋金发小妞儿
Mmm.
你知道的
You know...
迷恋像你这么漂亮的女人
...being a fool for a woman such as yourself...
绝对是明智之举
...is always the right thing to do.
若我还在经营妓院时
If we had met when I was back in business...
就认识了你
你一定会是…
...you would have been my number one lady.
我妓院里的大红牌
我受宠若惊
- Well, I'm flattered. - You goddamn well better be.
最好是…
这辆车我听说你开的是货车
This... I heard you were driving a truck.
我那辆猫咪小车挂了
My Pussy Wagon died on me.
猫咪死了
The Pussy died. Hmm.
比尔一枪打中你的头吗？
Bill shot you in the head, no?
对
- Yes. - Hmm.
换作是我就会好心一点
I would have been much nicer.
我只会割毁你的容貌
I would have just cut your face.
请你海涵
You must forgive me.
陪我喝一杯吧
Please... you have a drink with me.
克拉丽塔
Clara!
来了
Coming.
两杯龙舌兰
Dos a?ejo.
擦一下(西班牙语)
谢谢(西班牙语)
Gracias.
刚才说到哪儿了？
What were we talking about?
比尔
Bill.
比尔在哪儿？
- Where's Bill? - Where's Bill?
比尔在哪？
Yeah. Hmm.
比尔在四季别墅
Bill is at the Villa Quatro, on the road to Salina.
就在往萨莱纳的路上
我画张地图给你
I will draw you a map.
我把比尔当成自己的儿子
Bill is like a son to me.
你知道我为何要帮你吗？
- Do you know why I help you? - No.
不知道
Because he would want me to.
因为这是他的意思
我才不相信
Now, that I don't believe.
Ahh.
不然他要怎样才能再见到你？
How else is he ever going to see you again?
妈咪，不许动
Freeze, Mommy.
Bang, bang! Oh!
我们中弹了，宝贝，妈咪打中我们了
Oh! She got us, B.B.
Mommy got us. Oh, I'm dying!
我快死了
I'm dying.
快倒下，妈咪打中我们了
Fall down, sweetheart. Mommy shot us.
但神枪手小妞儿毫不知情
But little did Quickdraw Kiddo know that little B.B. was only playing possum,
小宝贝只是在装死
因为
due to the fact that she was impervious to bullets.
子弹根本伤不了她
妈咪，子弹伤不了我耶
I am pervious to bullets, Mommy.
躺好啦，你在装死
Hey, get back down there. You're playing possum.
所以冷笑的杀手还以为这是
So, as the smirking killer advanced on what she thought
一具被子弹打死的尸体
was a bullet-ridden corpse, that's when little B.B. fired.
此时小宝贝就开枪了
砰砰
Bang, bang!
妈咪，你死了
You're dead, Mommy. So die.
快死啊
Oh!
宝贝
B.B.
Oh! B.B...
宝贝
我早该知道的
I should've known.
你最厉害
You are... the best.
妈咪，不要死啦
Oh, Mommy. Don't die.
我只是在闹着玩的
I was just playing.
我知道
I know.
我跟她说你睡着了
I told her you were asleep...
但有一天你会醒过来
...but that one day you'd wake up and come back to her.
回来找她
她问我
And she asked me, "If Mommy's been asleep since I was born,
我一出生妈咪就睡着了
那她怎么知道我长什么模样？
then how will she know what I look like?"
我回答她说
To which I replied, "Because Mommy's been dreaming of you. "
因为妈咪会梦见你啊
我是这么回答的
That's what I said.
你有没有梦到我？我有梦到你耶
Did you dream of me? I dreamed of you.
我每天晚上都梦到你，宝贝
Every single night, baby. Every single night.
妈咪，我等了好久你才醒过来
I waited a long time for you to wake up, Mommy.
让我好好看看你
Now, let me look at you.
Oh.
天哪，好漂亮的小女孩
My, my, my, what a pretty little girl you are.
妈咪也很漂亮啊
You're pretty too, Mommy.
跟妈咪说我拿她的照片给你看
Tell Mommy what you said when I showed you her picture.
你怎么说的
Mnh-mnh.
说嘛，别害羞了
- Come on, shy girl. - Mnh-mnh.
快说啊，你怎么说的自己最清楚
Come on. You know what you said.
说啊
Come on. Tell Mommy. It'll make her feel good. Come on.
告诉妈咪，她一定会很开心
快说啊
- Mnh-mnh. - Yeah. Come on.
我说
I said... I said,
你是全世界最漂亮的大美女
"You're the most beautifulest woman I ever saw in the whole wide world. "
那是真的
That's the truth. That's what she said.
她就是这么说的
宝贝
B.B., don't you think Mommy has the prettiest hair in the whole wide world?
你不觉得妈咪的头发
是全世界最漂亮的吗？
对啊
- Yes, I do. - Matter of fact, it's better than pretty.
其实不只是漂亮而已
怎样形容才比漂亮更漂亮？
- What's better than pretty? - Mmm... Gorgeous.
美若天仙
Very good. Gorgeous. Mommy is gorgeous.
很好，美若天仙
妈咪美若天仙
Hmm. You know, sweetie, Mommy's kinda mad at Daddy.
甜心，妈咪在生爸爸的气
为什么？你是坏爸爸吗？
Why, Daddy? Were you being a bad daddy?
对啊
I'm afraid I was. I was a real bad daddy.
我是个很坏的爸爸
我们女儿前几天见识到了生与死
Our little girl learned about life and death the other day.
跟妈咪说埃米利奥怎么啦
Wanna tell Mommy about what happened to Emilio?
我杀死它
I killed him.
埃米利奥是她的金鱼
- Emilio was her goldfish. - Emilio was my goldfish.
埃米利奥是我的金鱼
她跑进我房间
She came running into my room, holding the fish in her hand and crying,
手里捧着鱼哭着说
爸爸，埃米利奥死掉了
"Daddy. Daddy. Emilio's dead. "
我说：“真的吗？好可怜啊”
And I said, "Really? That's so sad.
他是怎么死的？
How did he die?"
你怎么回答我？
- And what did you say? - I stepped on him.
我踩到它了
这位小姐
Actually, young lady, the words you so strategically used were,
其实你技巧性的回答是：
我不小心踩到它了
"I accidentally stepped on him. "
于是我就质疑
To which I queried,
你的脚怎么会不小心
"And just how did your foot accidentally find its way into Emilio's fishbowl?"
踩进埃米利奥的鱼缸里？
她说：“不是啦”
And she said, "No, no, no. Emilio was on the carpet when I stepped on him. "
踩到时埃米利奥是在地毯上
剧情愈来愈紧张了
Mmm. The plot thickens.
埃米利奥怎么会在地毯上呢？
"And just how did Emilio get on the carpet?"
妈咪，你一定会以她为傲
And, Mommy, you would've been so proud of her.
她没撒谎
She didn't lie.
她说她把埃米利奥从鱼缸抓出来
She said she took Emilio out of his bowl...
把它放在地毯上
...and put him on the carpet.
埃米利奥在地毯上做什么？
And whatwas Emilio doing on the carpet?
一直跳
Flapping.
然后你就用力踩它
- And then you stomped on him. - Uh-huh.
等你把脚抬起来以后
And when you lifted up your foot...
埃米利奥在做什么？
- ... what was Emilio doing then? - Nothing.
没做什么
He stopped flapping, didn't he?
它没再跳了，对不对？
她后来告诉我
She told me later...
她抬起脚时看到埃米利奥没在跳
...that the second she lifted up her foot
and saw Emilio not flapping, she knew what she had done.
她就知道自己做了什么事
这不正是生与死的完美实例吗？
Is that not the perfect visual image of life and death?
金鱼在地毯上一直跳
A fish flapping on the carpet, and a fish not flapping on the carpet.
金鱼在地毯上没在跳
如此强烈的意象
So powerful, even a four-year-old with no concept of life or death...
就连不懂何谓生死的四岁小孩
都知道这代表了什么
...knew what it meant.
你很爱埃米利奥吧？
- You loved Emilio, didn't you? - Uh-huh.
我也爱妈咪
Well... I love Mommy too.
但我对妈咪和你对埃米利奥一样
But I did to Mommy what you did to Emilio.
你用力踩妈咪？
- You stomped on Mommy? - Worse.
更糟糕
我枪杀了妈咪
I shot Mommy.
不是像我们刚才那样假装开枪
Not pretend shooting like we were just doing.
我是真的开枪射她
I shot her for real.
为什么？你想知道会怎样吗？
Why? Did you want to see what would happen?
不是，我知道开了枪妈咪会怎样
No, I knew what would happen to Mommy if I shot her.
我不知道的是
What I didn't know was, when I shot Mommy, what would happen to me.
我枪杀了妈咪之后我会怎样
结果是怎样？
- What happened? - I was very sad.
我很伤心
这是我学到的教训
And that's when I learned...
有些事一旦做了
...some things, once you do, they can never be undone.
就再也无法挽回了
妈咪怎么了？
- What happened to Mommy? - Why don't you ask Mommy?
你自己问妈咪啊
You OK, Mommy? Does it hurt?
妈咪，你还好吧？会不会痛？
不会
No, sweetie.
已经不痛了
Doesn't hurt anymore.
你有没有生病？
Did it make you sick?
没有
No. It made me sleep.
我只是睡着了
所以才不能陪你，因为我睡着了
That's why I haven't been with you. B.B. I've been asleep.
可是你现在醒了啊，对不对？
But you're awake now, Mommy. Right?
我非常清醒，漂亮宝贝
I'm wide awake, pretty girl.
宝贝，你要不要妈咪
B.B., would you like Mommy to watch a video with you before sleepy time?
陪你在睡觉前看录影带？
妈咪，你要不要陪我
Uh-huh.
Mommy, do you want to watch a video with me before sleepy time?
在睡觉前看录影带？
Oh, yeah! I would love to.
好啊，乐意之至
你想看哪一部？
- Which one do you wanna watch? - Shogun Assassin.
《刺杀大将军》
No, B.B. Shogun Assassin is too long.
不行，《刺杀大将军》太长了
- Mnh-mnh. - No, it's not.
不会啦
Well, then, I'll leave you ladies to it.
好吧
你们母女慢慢欣赏
在我小的时候
When I was little, my father was famous.
我爸很有名
他是全日本最伟大的武士
He was the greatest samurai in the empire.
他专门砍幕府将军的头
And he was the shogun's decapitator.
他砍了131个诸侯的头
He cut off the heads of 131 lords.
我爸事后会回家找我妈
My father would come home to Mother and when he would see her,
当他看到妈咪时
就会忘记杀人的事
he would forget about the killings.
他不怕幕府将军
He wasn't scared of the shogun, but the shogun was scared of him.
但幕府将军很怕他
或许这正是问题所在吧
Maybe that was the problem.
有一天晚上
One night, the shogun sent...
幕府将军派了忍者间谍
我正在欣赏你的武士刀
I was just admiring your sword.
好一把上等名刀
Quite a piece of work.
对了，服部半藏还好吧？
Speaking of which, how is Hanzo-san?
他很好
He's good.
他做的寿司有没有比较好吃？
Has his sushi gotten any better?
我真不敢相信
You know, I couldn't believe it. You got him to make you a sword.
你居然说服他替你铸刀
很简单
It was easy. I just dropped your name, Bill.
我只是提了你的名字
这就够了啊
That'd do it.
你是打算用服部半藏的刀
I suppose the idea is we cross Hanzo swords. Am I right?
和我决一死战
对不对？
说来也巧
Well,
it just so happens this hacienda has its own private beach.
这栋别墅碰巧有私人海滩
而且皎洁的月光洒在私人海滩上
And that private beach just so happens to look particularly beautiful
美得令人眩目
bathed in moonlight.
今晚正好是满月之夜
And there just so happens to be a full moon out tonight.
持刀的武士
So, swordfighter, if you want a swordfight, that's where I suggest.
若你想用刀和我决斗
建议你选在这片海滩上
但你若想保守一点
But if you wanna be old school about it...
你也知道我这个人很保守
...and you know I'm all about old school...
那我们可以等到天亮
...then we could wait until dawn and slice each other up at sunrise
在旭日初升时拿刀互砍
像名副其实的两个…
like a couple of real-life honest...
现在
Now, if you don't settle down, I'm gonna have to put one in your kneecap.
你再不安分一点
我就在你膝盖骨上再补一枪
听说射在膝盖骨上超痛的
And I hear tell that's a very painful place to get shot in.
I'm just fuckin' with you.
跟你开个玩笑啦
现在
Now...
提到你的事
...when it comes to you...
还有我们的关系
...and us...
我有几个疑问想理清一下
...I have a few unanswered questions.
在这个血腥复仇故事
So, before this tale of bloody revenge reaches its climax,
演变到最高潮之前
我要问你几件事
I'm gonna ask you some questions, and I want you to tell me the truth.
希望你能实话实说
不过说到这里就很两难了
However, there in lies a dilemma.
因为只要提到我的事
Because when it comes to the subject of me,
我可以确定你百分之百
I believe you are truly and utterly incapable of telling the truth.
不可能实话实说
Especially to me. And least of all, to yourself.
尤其是在面对我时
反正你也会自欺欺人
只要提到我的事
And when it comes to the subject of me,
我可以确定你说的话
I am truly and utterly incapable of believing anything you say.
我连一个字都不会相信
这个难题怎么解决？
How do you suppose we solve this dilemma?
这个嘛
Well,
说来也巧
it just so happens,
我正好有办法解决
I have a solution.
一枪命中
- Aah! - Gotcha!
妈的！
Goddamn!
你是拿什么东西射我？
What the fuck did you just shoot me with?
我最伟大的发明
My greatest invention. Or at least my favorite.
至少是我最喜欢的
不准碰
Don't touch it, or I'll stick another one right in your cheek.
否则我在你脸颊上再补一箭
那根箭里面的药剂
What lies within that dart, just begging to course its way through your veins...
正在你的血液里流动
药效很强
...is an incredibly potent and quite infallible truth serum.
保证你会什么事都全盘托出
我称之为
I call it "The Undisputed Truth. "
“不争的事实”
药效是巴比妥盐麻醉剂的两倍
Twice as strong as sodium pentothal, with no druggie aftereffects.
又不会用药成瘾
只不过
Exceptfor a slight wave of euphoria. You feel it?
会出现幸福愉悦的幻觉
感觉到了吗？
- Euphoria? - Yeah.
幻觉？
对
- No. - Too bad.
没有
真可惜
你最了解我了
As you know...
我很喜欢看漫画书
...I'm quite keen on comic books.
尤其是有超级英雄的漫画书
Especially the ones about superheroes.
我对关于超级英雄的
I find the whole mythology surrounding superheroes fascinating.
所有故事都很感兴趣
以我最喜欢的超级英雄为例
Take my favorite superhero, Superman.
超人
不是什么好漫画书啦，画得不好
Not a great comic book. Not particularlywell drawn.
Mmm.
但整个故事
But the mythology...
整个故事不只是精彩还很特别
The mythology is not only great, it's unique.
这玩意儿要多久才会发挥药效？
How long does this shit take to go into effect?
差不多两分钟
About two minutes. Just long enough for me to finish my point.
正好足够让我说完重点
现在
Now, a staple of the superhero mythology is,
超级英雄神话里的基本要素是
要有超级英雄和他的另一面
there's the superhero and there's the alter ego.
蝙蝠侠的真实身份是布鲁斯・韦恩
Batman is actually Bruce Wayne, Spider-Man is actually Peter Parker.
蜘蛛侠是彼得・帕克
他早上一起床
When that characterwakes up in the morning, he's Peter Parker.
就是彼得・帕克了
他要换了衣服
He has to put on a costume to become Spider-Man.
才会变成蜘蛛侠
根据这一点
And it is in that characteristic Superman stands alone.
超人就是独一无二的了
超人不会变成超人
Superman didn't become Superman.
超人一生下来就是超人
Superman was born Superman.
超人早上一起床
When Superman wakes up in the morning, he's Superman.
他就是超人了
他的另一面是克拉克・肯特
His alter ego is Clark Kent.
他那件上面印着红色S的衣服
His outfitwith the big red "S" -
是肯特夫妇捡到弃婴身上的包巾
that's the blanket he was wrapped in as a baby when the Kents found him.
那是他的衣服
Those are his clothes.
肯特的打扮：戴眼镜、穿西装
What Kent wears - the glasses, the business suit - that's the costume.
那只是他的扮相
超人要打扮成这样
That's the costume Superman wears to blend in with us.
才能混进人群里
克拉克・肯特是超人眼里的我们
Clark Kent is how Superman views us.
克拉克・肯特有什么特征？
And what are the characteristics of Clark Kent?
他很孬种
He's weak...
没自信
...he's unsure of himself...
他是个胆小鬼
...he's a coward.
克拉克・肯特是超人
Clark Kent is Superman's critique on the whole human race.
对全体人类的观点
就好比比阿特丽克斯小妞儿
Sort of like Beatrix Kiddo and Mrs. Tommy Plimpton.
和汤米・普林顿太太
原来如此
Aso.
你说到重点了
The point emerges.
你可以打扮成艾琳・普林顿
You would've worn the costume of Arlene Plimpton.
但你一生下来就是比阿特丽克斯小妞儿
But you were born Beatrix Kiddo.
你每天早上起床时
And every morning when you woke up, you'd still be Beatrix Kiddo.
还是比阿特丽克斯小妞儿
箭可以拔掉了
Oh, you can... take the needle out.
你认为我是超级英雄吗？
Are you calling me a superhero?
我认为你是个杀手
I'm calling you a killer.
天生的闪灵杀手
A natural born killer.
你一直都是
You always have been, and you always will be.
将来也不会改变
就算搬去埃尔帕索
Moving to El Paso...
在二手唱片行上班
...working in a used record store...
和汤米一起去看电影
...goin' to the movies with Tommy...
从报纸上剪印花
...clipping coupons.
都只是你
That's you...
想把自己伪装成一只工蜂
...trying to disguise yourself as a worker bee.
你想混进蜂群里
That's you tryin' to blend in with the hive.
但你不是工蜂
But you're not a worker bee.
你是叛变的杀人蜂
You're a renegade killer bee.
不管你喝了多少啤酒
And no matter how much beer you drank or barbecue you ate
吃了多少烤肉
or how fat your ass got,
或是屁股变得多大
nothing in the world would ever change that.
再怎么样也改变不了事实
第一个问题
First question:
你觉得洗心革面去了埃尔帕索
Did you really think your life in El Paso was gonna work?
就能重新开始吗？
不行
No!
但我可以陪着宝贝长大
But I would've had B.B.!
别误解我的意思
Don't get me wrong.
我相信你会是个好妈咪
I think you would have been a wonderful mother.
但你是个杀手
But you are a killer.
你杀了这么多人才找到我
All those people you killed to get to me...
感觉很爽吧？
...felt damn good, didn't they?
对
Yes.
杀死每一个人都很爽？
Every single one of them?
对
Yes.
这个问题只是让你暖暖身
That was the warmup round.
现在要问的是
Now comes the $64,000 question.
价值百万奖金的大问题
为何怀了我的孩子又弃我而去？
Why did you run away from me with my baby?
还记得你派给我的最后任务吗？
Do you rememberthe last assignment you sent me on?
当然记得
Of course.
王丽莎
Lisa Wong.
我启程的那天早上觉得不太舒服
The morning I left, I was sick.
我在飞机上呕吐了
On the plane, I threw up.
于是我开始怀疑
So I started thinking:
我可能怀孕了
Maybe I was pregnant.
用法简单
"Easy to use. Remove cap and urinate on the absorbent end for five seconds.
取下盖子用尿液浸湿棉棒五秒钟
等九十秒就能准确地验孕
"Accurate results in only 90 seconds.
对照窗出现一条线即可判读结果
You can read the results as soon as the line appears in the window. "
真该死
Fuck.
我当时并不知道
What I didn't know...
我在途中已经被人发现了
...was that somewhere on my journey I had been spotted.
我才到洛杉矶，王丽莎随即…
With me in L.A., it didn't take Lisa Wong long to send an assassin of her own.
派了人来暗杀我
请问有什么事？
Hello, can I help you?
我是饭店的公关经理金凯伦
Hello, I'm Karen Kim. I'm the hospitality manager ofthe hotel.
我送迎宾礼来给你
I have a welcome gift from the management.
谢谢
Oh, that's nice. Um...
放在门口就好了
Can you just leave it by the door?
你是霰弹枪神射手吗？
- You pretty good with that shotgun? - Not that I have to be at this range,
这么近随便射都中
但我是霰弹枪神射手
but I'm a fuckin' surgeon with this shotgun.
贱人，你猜怎么着
Well, guess what, bitch? I'm better than Annie Oakley.
我的枪法神准，已经瞄准你了
- And I got you right in my sight. - I could blow your fuckin' head off.
我可以一枪打烂你的脑袋
我会抢先命中你的眉心
Not before I put one right between your eyes, so let's talk.
所以还是谈谈吧
凯伦
Karen...
我刚才发现
...I justfound out...
就在刚才
...right now...
在你一枪把门打穿之前没多久
...not a moment before you blew a hole through the door...
我发现自己怀孕了
- ... that I'm pregnant. - What is this?
你在耍什么花招？
在门边的地上
On the floor by the door...
有验孕棒可以证明我怀孕了
...is a strip that says I'm pregnant.
胡扯
Bullshit.
以前你这么说是对极了
Any other time you'd be 100 percent right.
但这次
This time...
你是大错特错了
...you're 100 percent wrong.
我是全世界最可怕的女杀手
I'm the deadliest woman in the world.
但现在
But right now...
我为了肚子里的宝宝心惊胆颤
...I'm just scared shitless for my baby.
求求你
Please.
看看验孕棒吧
Just look at the strip.
求求你
Please.
待在原地，不准轻举妄动
Stay where you are and don't move.
这玩意儿我看不懂啦
I don't know what this fuckin' shit means.
旁边的包装盒上有说明
The box with the directions - it's right there.
用法简单
"Easy to use.
取下盖子用尿液浸湿棉棒五秒钟
Remove the cap and urinate on the absorbent end. "
蓝色就表示怀孕了
Blue means pregnant.
我自己会看，不用你多事
I'll read it myself, thank you.
好吧
Oh, OK.
就算我相信你，那又怎样？
Say I were to believe you. What then?
你回家吧
Just go home.
我也回家
I'll do the same.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
在验孕棒呈现蓝色之前
Before that strip turned blue...
我是个女人，而且是你的女人
...I was a woman, I was your woman.
我是杀手，奉你之命去杀人
I was a killer who killed for you.
在验孕棒呈现蓝色之前
Before that strip turned blue, I would've jumped a motorcycle
我会骑摩托车跳上高速列车
onto a speeding train.
只为了你
For you.
但在验孕棒呈现蓝色之后
But once that strip turned blue...
我就再也做不到了
...I could no longer do any ofthose things.
再也做不到
Not anymore.
因为我要当母亲了
Because I was gonna be a mother.
你懂吗？
Can you understand that?
我懂
Yes.
但你当时为什么不说
But why didn't you...
到现在才告诉我？
...tell me then, instead of now?
你知道了一定会带走她
Once you knew, you'd claim her.
我不想那样
And I didn'twant that.
这不是你能决定的
Not your decision to make.
对
Yes.
但这是明智的决定
But it's the right decision, and I made it for my daughter.
我为我女儿作了决定
她理应生长在平凡清白的家庭里
She deserved to be born with a clean slate.
但和你在一起
But with you...
她要生在不适合她成长的环境里
...she would've been born into a world she shouldn't have.
我必须抉择
I had to choose.
我选了她
I chose her.
五年前
You know, five years ago,
若要我列出一份名单
if I had to make a list of impossible things that could never happen,
列举永远不可能发生的事
你拿枪指着我的脑袋
you performing a coup de grace on me by bustin' a cap in my crown...
补上一枪结束我的苦难
这绝对是名单上的第一名
...would've been right at the top of the list.
我错了，对吧？
I'd have been wrong, wouldn't I?
抱歉
I- I'm sorry.
你是在问我吗？
Was that a question?
在永远不可能发生的事当中
Of impossible things that could never happen -
对，在此例中你是错了
yes, in this instance you would've been wrong.
为什么？
Well?
你一直没有回来找我
When you never came back,
我的直觉反应就是
I naturally assumed Lisa Wong, or somebody else, had killed you.
王丽莎，或者其他什么人杀了你
对了，你没死
Oh! And for the record...
却让我以为自己心爱的人死了
...letting somebody think somebody they love is dead when they're not
是一件很残忍的事
is quite cruel.
我替你哀悼了三个月
I mourned you forthree months.
在哀悼你的第三个月
And in the third month of mourning you...
我找到了你
...I tracked you down.
我不是特地去找你
I wasn't tryin' to track you down.
我本来想找的是...
I was tryin' to track down the fucking assholes I thought killed you.
我以为杀了你的混帐凶手
最后我找到了你
So I find you...
结果呢？
...and what do I find?
你不只没死
Not only are you not dead...
还要结婚了
...you're getting married to some fucking jerk.
嫁给一个该死的混蛋
而且你还怀孕了
And you're pregnant.
我反应过度了
I overreacted.
你反应过度了？
You overreacted? Is that your explanation?
这就是原因？
I didn't say I was gonna explain myself.
我不是在替自己辩解
我只是在陈述事实
I said I was gonna tell you the truth.
若这样说你还听不懂
But if that's too cryptic, let's get literal.
那就讲得白话一点
我是个杀手
I'm a killer.
我是个杀人魔，你心里有数
I'm a murdering bastard. You know that.
伤了杀人魔的心
And there are consequences...
要付出很大的代价
...to breaking the heart of a murdering bastard.
你已经付出一部份的代价了
You experienced some of them.
我的反应让你那么意外吗？
Was my reaction really that surprising?
没错
Yes. It was.
你能做之前做的那些事吗？
Could you do what you did?
当然可以
Of course you could.
但我做梦也没想到
But I never thought you would, or could, do that to me.
你会这样对我，或可能这样对我
我很抱歉，小妞儿
I'm really sorry, Kiddo...
你错看我了
...but you thought wrong.
我们还有旧债未清
You and I have unfinished business.
宝贝，你说得对极了
Baby... you ain't kiddin'.
白眉传授了你...
Pai Mei taught you the Five-Point-Palm Exploding-Heart Technique?
独门的五步穿心指？
没错
'Course he did.
你怎么没告诉我？
Why didn't you tell me?
我不知道
I don't know.
因为我...
Because I'm...
我是个坏人
...a bad person.
不对
No.
你不是坏人
You're not a bad person.
你是个大好人
You're a terrific person.
你是我最喜欢的人
You're my favorite person.
但偶尔也有时候
But every once in a while...
你实在是讨厌极了
...you can be a real cunt.
我看起来怎样？
How do I look?
你看起来准备好了
You look ready.
“隔天早上”
Well, well, well. If it ain't the little flower.
原来是一朵小花啊
各位美国人和海上的船只大家好
Good evening, Mr. and Mrs. America and all the ships at sea.
要报新闻了，新闻快报
Let's go to press. Flash.
你家里有喜鹊吗？
Do you have a magpie in your home?
若是有就恭喜你了
If you do, you are most fortunate.
喜鹊是全世界最可爱的小鸟
The magpie is the most charming bird in all the world.
也是农夫最好的朋友
He is the best friend a farmer ever had.
温柔地对待它
Treat him gently. Treat him kindly.
好好地对待它
一定要记住
And always remember, the magpie deserves your respect.
你要尊重喜鹊才行
感谢老天
Thank you.
Thank you. Thank you.
感谢老天
Oh, thank you.
我来说说换作我会怎么做
Now, I'll tell you what I'm gonna do.
我的头又不痛
I ain't got no headache.
你有头痛啦
Oh yes, you have, brother.
“母狮子和她的小狮子团聚了”
“丛林里又回复了平静”
打板
开拍！
And, action!
卡！
Cut.
重来一次
Oh, come on. Let's do it again.